ANDRE PEIXOTO

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Phone: +55 18 99790-9068

Email: hi@andrepeixoto.dev

Website: andrepeixoto.dev

LinkedIn: andrempeixoto

Github: andrempeixoto

PROFILE

From the moment I first created a personalized version of an IRC messenger (year 1.999) to writing modern JavaScript code in 2024, I have to say programming has been a lifelong passion. Currently developing modern and performatic PWA apps, I'm excited to use my skills for creating meaningful apps that generate value and revenue.

Below you'll find some projects I've completed that showcase my skills and general background in software development.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Vue.js
- React.js
- Node.js
- Jest/TDD
- Electron
- Flutter/Dart
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Agile/Scrum
- Jira

- Linux
- Windows
- Portuguese
- English

PROJECTS

AMAZON.COM WEBSITE CLONE

- Amazon.com website clone created with ReactJS on the front-end, Stripe for handling payment authentication and Firebase for storing order's history.
- · Available here.

VETERINARY CLINIC WEBSITE

- · An institutional website made for Pequenos Animais veterinary clinic.
- · Built with React.JS
- The website is currently under development.
- Preview version deployed here.

TO-DO APP

- A to-do list app for listing daily activities to get completed.
- Built with React.JS
- Available here.

E-LEARNING PLATFORM

- An e-learning platform build with ReactJS (front-end), Node.js (backend), and sqlite3 for its database;
- · Available here.

EDUCATION

GOSTACK BOOTCAMP (MERN) FullStack Web/Mobile, Rocketseat Education, 2021

COMPUTER SCIENCE (CS50X)

Software Development, HarvardX, 2021

BUSINESS MANAGEMENT

MBA, Toledo University Center, 2013

BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES

Bachelor's, Northern Parana State University, 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - PRESENT

TwiageFull-time

FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- With three years at Twiage, I've been actively contributing to the development of web applications using Vue 2, Vue 3 and Node.js, and participating in cross-platform projects with Electron and Flutter.
- Collaborating effectively with a remote team in project specifications, design, and management. Additionally, I supervised interns, fostering a collaborative learning environment. My journey highlights technical expertise and effective leadership.

2021 - 2021

NuoMed Full-time

FLUTTER DEVELOPER

- Worked in the early phases of a tele-medicine startup, actively contributing to the creation of a cross-platform app using Flutter and Dart.
- Undertaking both front and back-end programming, I collaborated on shaping the UX design, marking a personally and professionally significant chapter in my journey as a developer.

2017 - 2019

Igreja Prudentina Part-time

IT COORDINATOR

 Coordinated media and communication department (sound operation, video streaming of services and courses, monthly newsletters editing, website's development and maintenance).

2015 - 2021

Pequenos Animais Part-time

IT COORDINATOR & BUSINESS ADVISOR

 Conducted IT management, such as network and applications support, in person and remotely, as well as business consulting services, aiming greater ROI & customer satisfaction.

2014 - 2015

IBM

Full-time

CUSTOMER SUPPORT SPECIALIST

 Provided remote support for Hardware and Services divisions located in the United States, from Brazil's IBM plant through email, chat and phone.

2011 - 2014

Pequenos Animais

Full-time

ADMINISTRATIVE MANAGER

- Developed many initiatives in the IT field for the company regarding its internal communication and scheduling systems (GSuite, web apps, and local network);
- Lead processes' and departments' reorganization and improvement;
- Engaged on the company's brand strengthening, improving and modernizing its marketing initiatives and digital presence.